{
    "id": "f4865dee46d84834abf60213bcac235c",
    "title": "Can and Could Special Uses",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ae807d03724f46cbba057f186f582ad4",
            "title": "Can and Could Special Uses",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I ....................... Mary coming.",
                    "description": "When the verb see refers to perception, we do not normally use continuous forms.",
                    "answers": [
                        "can see",
                        "am seeing",
                        "see"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………….. somebody coming up the stairs?",
                    "description": "When the verb hear refers to perception, we do not normally use progressive forms.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Are you hearing",
                        "Can you hear"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did you put in the soup? I ………………… something funny.",
                    "description": "When the verb taste refers to perception, we do not normally use progressive forms.",
                    "answers": [
                        "taste",
                        "am tasting",
                        "can taste"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Suddenly I realized I ……………….. something burning.",
                    "description": "When the verb smell refers to perception, we do not normally use progressive forms.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was smelling",
                        "could smell"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… what she wanted.",
                    "description": "Know is not normally used with can/could.",
                    "answers": [
                        "knew",
                        "could knew",
                        "had known"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… what she wanted.",
                    "description": "Can and could are often used with the verb guess. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "guessed",
                        "could guess",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You ………………… she is British from her accent.",
                    "description": "The expression ‘can tell’ means 'know'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "tell",
                        "told",
                        "can tell"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ..................... what you are talking about.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "can't understand",
                        "don't understand",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is an arrogant woman, but somehow you can’t ………………… her.",
                    "description": "After can’t help, we use an -ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "help to like",
                        "help like",
                        "help liking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I couldn’t ………………. what they said.",
                    "description": "After can’t / couldn't help, we use an ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "help to overhear",
                        "help overhearing",
                        "help overhear"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I can’t help ...................... what she wants.",
                    "description": "After can’t help, we can use ‘but + infinitive without to’. This expression has the same meaning as ‘can’t help + ing form’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "but to wonder",
                        "but wonder",
                        "but wondering"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I can't help .......................... what I should do next.",
                    "description": "The expression 'can't help + ing' has the same meaning as the expression 'can't help but + infinitive without to'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "but wonder",
                        "wondering",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}